# **Daniel Burgess**

Full Stack Developer

Phone: 0434 869 784

Email: dan-buraess@hotmail.com

Location: Adelaide SA DOB: 10/10/1993

Portfolio and Links: github.com/DBurgess93 danielburgessportfolio.herokuapp.com linkedin.com/in/daniel-burgess-668176186/

# **Professional Summary**

Ambitious, reliable and functionality first Full-Stack Developer. Looking to engage in a new team environment and apply programming skills, as well as build upon knowledge base in the interest of ongoing improvement. Graduate of Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp, skilled in both front-end and back-end programming languages/frameworks, as well as databases to build fully functional web applications with a focus on user experience and optimal performance. Portfolio includes both team and individual projects taken from initial design to deployment, using tools to track progress and organise team workflow.

Previous work includes 8 years in sales and customer relations roles, 6 years in heavily team-based roles, experience in teaching workplace processes, leading small teams and working autonomously.

Previous employees would endorse for having a great attitude, being a hard worker, a people person and someone who is curious and eager to learn.

# Summary of Skills

## Technical Skills

- JavaScript
- React.JS
- Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL
- Firebase
- HTML5
- css/scss
- Bootstrap
- Figma
- · REST API and web scraping
- Web hosting using Heroku
- GitHub
- Trello Workflow and Task Tracking

## Soft Skills

- Great communication/People Person
- Organisation
- Collaborative Mindset
- Leadership Qualities
- Adaptability
- Problem solving
- Curiosity
- Highly Personable

# **Education**

#### **WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE 2022**

Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp - Bali

## **DIPLOMA OF REMEDIAL MASSAGE 2015**

Endeavour College of Natural Health

## **HIGH SCHOOL GRADUATE - 2011**

Nuriootpa High School

# **Top Projects**

# **Deepwork**

- A Web-app designed to help students track how they spend their study time, analyse their data for a better understanding of their studying habits and motivate them to reach a state of deep focus.
- Tech-stack: Ruby on Rails, SASS, HTML, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Figma.

### **De-fit**

- A Web-app built to help bring together those who are in need of a fitness space and those who have one to share.
- Tech-stack: Ruby on Rails, SASS, HTML, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Figma.

## **IGNFY (I've Got News for You)**

- A Web-app built for users to showcase to their friends and followers the "breaking news" that's happening in their lives.
- Tech-stack: ReactJS, Typescript, Firebase, CSS, HTML, JavaScript.
- First app of mine built with React.JS and TypeScript.

# Full Stack Open (online course)

Currently working through the University of Helsinki's 'Full Stack Open'
course specifically to build single page applications with React.JS and
strengthen knowledge of testing, configuration, environment
management, and using databases.

# **Work Experience**

## Internal Sales | Amorini Australia | Aug 2021 - Sep 2022

- Managing all custom-made kitchen parts for every order.
- First point of call for customers, communicating to ensure custom products meet specification requirements.
- Improving online portal structures for kitchen sales software.
- Logistics Coordinating stock compiling for orders to be sent to site and between factories, tracking stock holdings and re-orders.
- Data entry using Servicem8 and EQ Business Management Software.

# Sales Rep | Camfil Australia (Airepure) | Jun 2018 - Dec 2019

- Building and maintaining customer relations through Sales calls and communication.
- Collaborated with internal engineering teams to provide product and technical advice to customers.
- Improving manufacturing processes, managing customer expectations.
- Reading through tender documents and quoting for projects from mechanical contractors.
- Sales research to secure early sales/tenders.
- Logistics co-ordination, Stock control, re-ordering.
- Data entry using Sage Accpac and Realtime Logistics.

## Remedial Therapist | Own Business | Mar 2014 - Jun 2018

- Providing Remedial services to clients
- Business management.
- Point of sale and invoicing using Square.
- Growing and maintaining client base through advertising, networking and social media engagement.
- Appointment tracking using various software products including Power Diary and Cliniko Practice Management.

#### Other Roles

Support Worker | Own Business | March 2023 - Present Mapping operator | Voxel Maps | Jan 2023 - Mar 2023 Cellar hand | Treasure Wine Estates | Jan 2020 - Aug 2021 Delivery Driver | OzHarvest | April 2020 - Oct 2020 Duty Manager | Barossa Rex Centre | Jan 2012 - Aug 2015